Friends,family, we're gathered to celebrate...
各位親朋好友 今天大家齊聚一堂
...the joyous union of Ross and Emily.
慶祝羅斯與艾蜜莉締結良緣
Now,Ross,repeat after me.
羅斯，請跟我覆述
"l,Ross."
我，羅斯…
I,Ross.
"Take thee,Emily."
娶你，艾蜜莉…
Take thee,Rachel.
娶你，瑞秋…
艾蜜莉
是艾蜜莉
Shall I go on?
要繼續嗎？
He said,"Rachel," right?
他說瑞秋對不對？
Do you think I should go up there?
我要過去嗎？
Yes. Yes. Do go on.
請繼續
I think we'd better start again.
我們最好重新來過
Repeat after me.
羅斯，請你跟著我說
"l,Ross."
我，羅斯…
I,Ross.
"Take thee,Emily."
娶你，艾…蜜…莉…
Take thee,Emily.
娶你，艾蜜莉…
Like there'd be anybody else.
否則還有誰？
"As my lawfully wedded wife, in sickness and in health...
成為我的合法髮妻 無論貧病，
...till death parts us."
至死不渝
As my lawfully wedded wife, in sickness and in health...
成為我的合法髮妻 無論貧病，
...until death parts us.
至死不渝
Really,I do. Emily.
我願意，艾蜜莉
Do you have the rings?
請給我婚戒
Place this ring on Ross' finger...
艾蜜莉，為羅斯戴上戒指
...as a symbol of your bond everlasting.
象徵你永遠愛他
Ross,place this ring...
羅斯，
...on Emily's hand as a symbol...
為艾蜜莉戴上戒指
...of the love that encircles you forever.
代表你倆白頭偕老
Happy to.
我很樂意
They have made their declarations...
羅斯與艾蜜莉已經宣誓
...and it gives me great pleasure to declare them husband and wife.
我很榮幸宣佈他們成為夫妻
You may kiss the bride.
你可以親吻新娘了
This is worse than when he married the lesbian.
這比他娶同性戀那次更糟糕
Just keep smiling.
保持微笑
Well,that went well.
好，進行得真順利
It could've been worse. He could've shot her.
他沒開槍殺死她就不錯了
That was pretty funny,wasn't it?
剛剛真耍寶
The One After Ross Says "Rachel"
本集播出：「陰錯陽差」
rainystar壓制ipod-mp4
懷念那一個夏天
還有那時候的那個人
You spoiled everything! It's a nightmare!
你搞砸所有事情 我丟死人了
My friends and family are out there! How can I face them?
我的親朋好友都在場 我以後拿什麼臉見人？
你怎麼做得出來？
No matter what happens with them...
無論如何
...we still get cake,right?
我們都吃得到蛋糕吧？
That's all right. You take your time. I'll be right out here.
沒關係，親愛的，你慢慢來 我在外面等你
She's just fixing her makeup.
她要補妝
I hate you!
我恨你
And I love you!
我也愛你
A bad time to say the wrong name,huh?
羅斯，你偏挑這個時候 說錯名字
That's true. Thanks,Dad.
你說得對，謝了，老爸
People should be dancing.
大家應該跳舞啊
This is a party! Come on!
這是婚宴，
Joey! Dance!
喬伊，跳舞啊
Yes,Waltham lnteriors.
沃森室內設計
This is Ross Geller's personal physician,Dr. Filangie.
你好，我是羅斯蓋勒的醫生 費蘭吉
Who?
誰？
I discovered that Ross forgot to take his brain medicine.
我發現羅斯忘了吃錯亂藥
Without it,in the brain of Ross...
他這人不吃藥
...women's names are interchangeable.
就有可能講錯女人的名字
Through no fault of his own.
這完全不能怪他
Oh,my God! Phoebe.
是菲比你啊
No,not Phoebe. Dr. Filangie.
我不是菲比，是費蘭吉醫生
Oh,no! You have it too!
你也錯亂了
What kind of bitch hangs up on a doctor?
什麼臭女人敢掛醫生的電話？
嘿 嗨
I hope you don't take this the wrong way...
希望你別誤會
...but I know we had plans to meet up tonight.
我知道我們今晚約了要見面
I'm worried about what it might do to our friendship.
但是我擔心以後做不成朋友
I know.
我明白
-How could we have let this happen? -Seven times!
我們怎麼這麼不小心 還不小心了七次
You know,look. We were away.
你知道，我們人在國外
In a foreign,romantic country.
又是浪漫的異鄉
I blame London.
都怪倫敦不好
Bad London!
壞倫敦
So look...
...while we're still in London, we can keep doing it,right?
既然我們還在倫敦 就可以繼續，對不對？
Well,I don't see that we have a choice.
看來我們別無選擇
But when we're back home, we don't do it.
但是我們回去就得停止
Only here.
只有這裡例外
You know,I saw a wine cellar downstairs.
我看到樓下有酒窖
I'll meet you there in two minutes.
我兩分鐘後下去找你 好
Mon? I gotta ask you something.
我有事情要問你
Now?
現在？
Ross said my name. I can't just pretend it didn't happen.
羅斯剛剛說出我的名字 我不能假裝沒聽到吧
I don't know.
我不知道
Monica,what should I do?
摩妮卡，我該怎麼辦？
Just do the right thing.
不要行差踏錯就行了
What?
什麼？
Tow the line! Thread the needle! Think outside the box!
聽天由命，努力爭取 不要死心眼
I'll talk to Ross about what he thinks it meant.
等等，我要問羅斯 他是什麼意思
Wait! Rachel,no.
瑞秋，
He's married.
他結婚了，
Married.
結婚了
If you don't realize that, I can't help you.
要是你還不懂，我也沒法幫你
Okay. You're right.
你說得對，
You're right. You can't help me.
你說得對，你幫不了我
Jack,is it all our fault? Were we bad parents?
傑克，這是我們的錯嗎？ 沒把小孩教好？
對
Who serves steak when there's no place to sit?
沒地方坐還叫人吃牛排
How are you supposed to eat this?
這要怎麼搞？
Hey,what's up?
你們好
You and me,next dance?
下首音樂跟我跳？
Sorry,dear, I only dance when I'm drunk.
抱歉，我只有喝醉才跳舞
Want me to get you something?
你想喝點什麼？
We were supposed to meet.
你跑哪去了？不是約在酒窖？
-Forget it. That's off. -Why?
算了，當我沒說。為什麼？
The next tour of the wine cellar...
兩分鐘後…
...will commence in two minutes.
為各位介紹酒窖
Joey,what are you doing?
喬伊，你搞什麼？
You promised,no meat till Phoebe has the babies.
你答應菲比等她生完才吃肉
We're in another country, so it doesn't count.
既然我們在國外就不算
-True. -He's got a point.
那倒是 他說得對
嗨
I'm sorry things aren't working out.
抱歉，事情竟然出狀況
It could be better. It'll be okay,right?
的確不太妙，不過會解決的
Oh,yeah! Of course. She'll get over this.
當然，她不會放在心上
So you said my name.
你脫口說出我的名字又如何
You just said it because you saw me there.
不過是因為你剛好看到我
If you'd seen a circus freak, you would've said:
如果你是看到怪胎
"l take thee,Circus Freak."
也會說：我娶你，怪胎
It didn't mean anything. It's a mistake.
根本沒有別的意思 只是無心之過
It didn't mean anything. Right?
沒有別的意思，對吧？
Oh,no! Of course it didn't mean anything.
當然沒有
I can understand why Emily thought it meant something...
但是我明白艾蜜莉為何誤會
...because it was you.
因為這剛好是你的名字
But it absolutely didn't. It didn't! It didn't!
沒錯， 其實沒有意義，真的沒有
The band's ready for your first dance with Emily.
羅斯，樂隊正在 等你跟艾蜜莉開舞
Oh! The band's ready!
樂隊準備好了
We've got to do what the band says. I don't care about the stupid band!
我們最好聽樂隊的話 我才不在乎哩
You spit on me,man!
你口水噴到我了
I'm sorry.
對不起
Emily is taking kind of a long time.
艾蜜莉也進去太久了吧
When I locked myself up at my wedding...
我結婚時也躲在廁所不出來
...I was trying to pop the window out of the frame.
不過那是因為我要撬開窗戶
Get the hell out of there. You know?
我一心想要逃出去
艾蜜莉，艾蜜莉
I'm coming in!
我要進去了
Oh,look at that. Same thing.
你看，同一招
In the middle of everything, if I scream,"Yippee!" just ignore me.
如果我中途大喊「好耶」 你就當作沒聽到
-Oh,my God! Rachel! -Oh,hello,Rachel.
天啊，瑞秋，嗨，瑞秋
Ross said my name.
羅斯叫出我的名字，
Okay? My name!
是我耶
Ross said my name up there.
他會說成我的名字
That obviously means he still loves me!
表示他還愛我
Don't believe me. I know I'm right.
不信就算了，我絕對沒誤會
Do you guys want to go and get a drink?
你們要不要下樓喝一杯？
Yes,we do.
好啊，
But we have to change first.
不過我們要先換衣服
Yes,I want to change.
對，我想換衣服
-Go get a table. -We'll only be five minutes.
你先下去佔位子 我們五分鐘就下去
Fifteen minutes.
十五分鐘吧
好
Oh,Phoebe! It's Phoebe!
喂，菲比啊，是菲比
-Oh,hey,hey. -Oh,great.
是嗎？ 太好了
嗨
So,what happened?
怎麼樣？
Well,Ross said my name.
羅斯說成我的名字
But I don't think that means anything.
我知道，不過他是無心的
Let's look at this objectively.
菲比，我們冷靜客觀想想看
Ninth grade,right?
他從國三就暗戀我
The obsession starts.
那時就瘋狂迷上我
Then he sees me in a two-piece for the first time.
那年暑假 他頭一次看我穿兩件式
His obsession begins to grow,right?
更是不可自拔愛上我
Why don't we go change in my room?
去我房間換衣服好了
My clothes are....
可是我的衣服在…
Wow,you look
你看起來真是…
No time for that.
沒時間廢話了
Hey,dude! Let me in! I got a girl out here!
老兄，讓我進去，我有女伴
I got a girl in here!
我也有
No,you don't. I saw you go in with Monica.
才怪，我看到你跟摩妮卡進去
Well,we're hanging out.
我們在裡面聊天
Which one of us will be having sex in there? Me or you?
你說我們誰有機會嘿咻？
I suppose I would have to say you.
看來我只能說是你了
-What if we're watching a movie? -Which we are!
可是我們正在看電視
And we've paid for it.
沒錯，我們付費了
It's My Giant.
正在看「我的巨人」
My Giant?
「我的巨人」？
I love that movie!
我愛死那部片
Think this is okay?
你確定這樣好嗎？
Well,Ross and Emily aren't going to use it.
反正羅斯跟艾蜜莉也用不到
Oh,it's so beautiful!
這裡好漂亮
I don't feel right about this.
可是我總覺得不太妥當
小摩…聽我說
This is the honeymoon suite.
這是蜜月套房
The room expects sex.
本來就該有人在這裡嘿咻
The room would be disappointed if it didn't get sex.
如果沒有，這間房一定很失望
All the other honeymoon suites would think it was a loser.
在其他蜜月套房面前抬不起頭
好吧 那好
Nope! Not under here!
沒有，沒看到
-You didn't find her? -I've looked everywhere.
你還沒找到她？我到處都找不到
You couldn't have, or you would've found her.
你一定漏掉什麼地方 否則早就找到了
-Keep looking! -Yeah! For about 30 minutes?
你應該繼續找 大概再找個30分鐘
Or 45?
或是45分鐘
In 45 minutes, you could find her twice.
45分鐘可以找到兩次了
For all I know,she's trying to find me but couldn't,because I kept moving.
不了，她一定也找不到我 因為我跑來跑去
From now on, I'm staying in one place.
從現在開始我不動了
Right here.
我就待在這裡
-It's getting late. -We're going to go.
時間晚了 我們要走了
Do you guys mind staying here for a while?
待一會兒如何？
We've got to get up early and catch that plane.
可是我們明天一早 就要搭機回紐約（音同捕捉）
Yeah,it's a very large plane.
而且那班飛機又很大
That's cool.
那就算了
But we'll stay here with you.
不過我們還是陪你一會
Thanks,guys!
謝了
I really appreciate this, but you don't need to rub my butt.
我很感激你們的好意 但是你也不用摸我屁股
We have to leave in an hour.
我們一小時後就要回紐約了
I know. I've been looking at those doors.
我知道 我一直在看那扇門
They look pretty soundproof, don't you think?
隔音效果似乎很好
We can't do that. That's insane.
不行，你瘋了
I mean,A,he could wake up. And B,you know...
第一，他可能醒來 第二，
...Iet's go for it.
管他的
艾蜜莉？艾蜜莉…
Nope.
不是她
-She's not with us. -We've come for her things.
不用找她了，她沒跟來 我們來拿她的東西
Where is she?
她在哪裡？
She's in hiding. She's humiliated. She doesn't want to see you again.
她躲起來了，因為她很丟臉 這輩子都不想再見到你
We're very sad that it didn't work out between you and Emily,monkey.
很遺憾你們兩個鬧成這樣 兔崽子
But I think you're absolutely delicious!
不過你實在是秀色可餐
Excuse me, I'm standing right here.
抱歉，我人還站在這裡
Oh,yes.
是啊，
There you are.
陰魂不散
Hurry up! Get some! There's a whole cart outside.
大家動作快，外面還有一車
Goodbye,Geller.
再見了，蓋勒
Now,hold on. Hold on.
等一下…
Your daughter and I are supposed to leave tonight for our honeymoon.
令嬡跟我今晚預定去度蜜月
Tell her I'll be at that airport, and I hope she will too.
請你們轉告她，我會去機場 我希望她也會去
I said Rachel's name, but it didn't mean anything.
我是說成瑞秋的名字 但這只是無心之過
She's just a friend.
她不過是我的朋友
Tell Emily I love her and...
就這樣，請轉告艾蜜莉 我愛她
...I can't imagine spending my life with anyone else.
我只想跟她共度餘生
Please,promise me that you'll tell her that.
請保證你們一定會轉告她
All right,I'll tell her.
我會告訴她，
Come on,bugger face!
走吧，臭婆娘
Call me.
打電話給我
You spend your life in the bathroom. Why do you never go out the window?
你也一天到晚待在廁所 怎麼就不會從窗戶滾蛋
Maybe it's best we never got to do it again.
或許我們不再上床才對
Yeah,it kind of makes that one night special.
否則那晚就不特別了
Technically,we still are over international waters.
理論上而言，我們還在海外
I'm going to the bathroom. Maybe I'll see you there?
我去洗手間，待會來找我？
好
Can I ask you something?
我可以問個問題嗎？
不行
Felicity and I watched My Giant. And I thought:
我昨晚跟費麗西蒂 一起看「我的巨人」
"I'll never be as good an actor as that giant."
我心想：自己永遠不可能 演得跟那個巨人一樣棒
Do you think I'm wasting my life with this acting thing?
我想當演員是否只是癡心妄想
The giant's five years younger than me.
那個巨人大概比我小五歲
You think I'll ever get there?
我有辦法跟他一樣優秀嗎？
會的
-Thanks,man. -Okay,man.
謝了 沒問題
But what about how much taller he is than me?
但是他比我高好多啊
I mean,there's no way I can make myself taller now.
我現在已經不可能再長高
Who knows what science will come up with in the future...
以後科學怎麼發展我不知道
...but what if I die an unsuccessful, regular-size man?
如果我死時只是一個 身高平庸的小人物呢？
You've been in the bathroom for a half-hour.
摩妮卡，你廁所上了半個小時
I know!
我知道
Had the beef tips,huh?
你也吃了牛肉？
嗨 嗨
嗨
You ate meat!
你吃過肉了
You had sex!
你跟人嘿咻
No,we didn't.
我們才沒有
I know you didn't. I was talking about Monica.
我知道你沒有 我說的是摩妮卡
I did not have sex.
菲比，我才沒跟人嘿咻
This pregnancy is throwing me all off and making me fat.
懷孕害我靈感不准 而且還變得胖嘟嘟
-I'll say hi to the chick and duck. -Me too!
我要去跟小雞小鴨打招呼 我跟你去
Why would you need to? You've been feeding them.
你何必去？ 你不是四天都去餵它們？
Oh,right. Maybe I'll just go home.
沒錯，我回家好了
We certainly are alone.
只剩下我們兩個
Good thing we have that "not New York" rule.
幸好我們說好回紐約就不行
沒錯
Listen,since we're on that subject...
既然你說到這個
...I just wanted to tell you that....
我想告訴你…
I was going through a hard time in London...
當時我在倫敦心情很不好
...with my brother getting married and that guy thinking I was Ross' mother.
因為哥哥結婚 別人還把我認作他媽
我知道
Well,anyway,I just....
那晚對我來說意義非凡
That night meant a lot to me. And I'm trying to say thanks.
我的意思是…我要謝謝你
You know,that night meant a lot to me too.
我那天也不是隨便上床
It wasn't because I was in a bad place or anything.
並不是因為我受到逼迫
It just meant a lot because you're really hot.
我很重視那晚是因為 你很性感
Is that okay?
這樣說可以嗎？
That's okay.
沒關係
And I'm cute too?
而且我也很帥
And you're cute too!
而且你也很帥
Thank you.
謝謝
All right,I gotta go unpack.
我要去整理行李了 好
再見
I'm still on London time. Does that count?
我時差還沒調回來 這表示我還在倫敦吧
-Oh,that counts! -Oh,good!
沒錯 太好了
瑞秋…
What are you doing here?
你怎麼會在這裡？
I've been on standby for a flight home for hours.
我在等候補機位回紐約
So no sign of Emily?
你還沒等到艾蜜莉？
Not yet.
還沒
When do you have to leave?
你是幾點的飛機？
This is the last call for flight 1066 to A thens.
最後一次呼叫 前往雅典的1066班機
The last call.
最後一次呼叫
Pretty soon,I guess.
就快了 是啊
I'm sorry.
我很遺憾
I don't understand.
我不明白
How could she do this?
她怎麼可以這麼做？
Am I a complete idiot for thinking she'd actually show up?
我是不是白癡？ 竟然以為她會來
You're not an idiot,Ross. You're a guy very much in love.
你不是白癡，羅斯 你只是愛得無可救藥
Same difference.
那還不是一樣
All passengers for flight 1066 to Athens should now be onboard.
搭乘1066班機 前往雅典的旅客請登機
I get it!
聽到了
Well,that's that.
沒搞頭了
No,you know what?
錯，
I think you should go.
你應該去
I think you should go...
什麼？ 對
...by yourself. Get some distance.
你應該自己去 到遙遠的地方想個清楚
Clear your head. It would be really good.
這對你一定有好處
I don't know.
我不知道…
Come on. It would be really good for you.
羅斯，你應該要去
I could do that.
沒錯，我應該去 對
I can't even believe her.
她實在太扯了
You know what? I am going to go.
知道嗎？我決定去了
-Good. -Why not?
很好 有何不可呢？
-Right? -Right.
對 對不對？沒錯
Thanks.
謝了
I'll see you back at home.
我們紐約見了
If I ever get a flight out of here.
希望我搭得上飛機
What? Wait,what?
其實…算了 怎麼了？
Why don't you come?
不如你也一起來
I mean,I have two tickets. Why not?
反正我有兩張機票
Well,I don't know,Ross. Really?
不太好吧？真的嗎？
Yeah. It'd be great. I mean,you can....
是啊，一定很好玩
You can lay on the beach...
你可以躺在海灘上
...and I can cry over my failed marriage.
我可以哭訴婚姻失敗
You see how I make jokes?
你看我多幽默啊
Really. I mean....
真的，
I could use a friend.
我需要有朋友陪我
Oh,wow. Maybe.
好吧，無妨
Yes,I can do that!
我可以陪你去
-Cool. -All right,cool.
好 好 太好了 是啊
走吧，拿去
Okay,we're going to Greece.
我們這就走
I forgot my jacket!
我忘了拿外套 等一下
Well,you tell them to wait.
你叫他們等一下
Wait! Wait!
等一下
艾蜜莉
不是啦…別走，艾蜜莉
I'll have a glass of Merlot...
我要梅洛紅酒
...and he'll have a wine spritzer.
這位要氣泡白酒
Look! The airport's moving.
你們看，機場在動
Are we moving?
飛機在動嗎？
Are we? Why are we moving?
飛機在動嗎？為什麼？
Does the captain know that we're moving?
機長知道飛機在動嗎？
Oh,my gosh!
天啊，老天爺
Mandarin-R3